business.govt.nz 2016-07-12

# Privacy | Business.govt.nz

## Purpose

The purpose of this privacy statement is to let users of **Business.govt.nz** know when we collect personal information and what we do with it. We do not use, share or disclose personal information collected or received through this website except as set out in this statement.

## Scope

This privacy statement applies to personal information collected through the Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment’s (MBIE) website: **Business.govt.nz.** It also includes how personal information is treated if you call our Business.govt.nz (MBIE) contact centre. **  
**

## Collection, storage and use

You can use **Business.govt.nz** without disclosing any personal information.

### Voluntary disclosure of personal information

You may choose to voluntarily provide personal information through this website (e.g. in comments, questions or feedback). This information will be viewable by site administrators, MBIE staff (as appropriate) and sometimes third-party contractors who administrate or work on the site.  

### Collection of personal information

MBIE may ask or require you (including where required by legislation administered by MBIE) to provide some personal information when you complete an online form (e.g. by submitting information to the Registrar through an online service, or through the site Contact form or a form to subscribe to site updates or news).

If you wish to apply for a job with us, you will be required to register your details with us in order to create an account, maintain a profile so we can match your skills and preferences against upcoming positions, apply for positions, sign up for and receive alerts, and manage any applications.  

### Holding of information

When you provide personal information, it will be held by MBIE. It may be stored or accessed on behalf of MBIE by authorised third parties (such as third-party contractors) to the extent that is necessary, for example for them to administrate or work on the site. We will store and keep it secure in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993 and agents will be subject to MBIE’s information security and privacy requirements.  

### Disclosure of information

MBIE will generally not share personal information that is provided or collected through this website, unless it is necessary to do so for the purpose for which you gave us the information (e.g. to investigate a complaint) or where you consent. MBIE will not otherwise disclose personal information provided or collected through this website unless required or otherwise permitted by law.

### Use of personal information

We will generally only use personal information provided to us through this website for the purpose you provided it (e.g. to administer, evaluate and improve the site, to improve our services and to action or respond to the information provided). We may also use personal information provided to us through this website for other reasons permitted under the Privacy Act (e.g. with your consent, for a directly related purpose, or where the law permits or requires it).

## Records and retention of personal information

MBIE will only retain personal information as long as it is required for the purposes for which the information may lawfully be used.

###   
Public records

Where any information provided (which may include personal information) to or through this site constitute public records, it will be retained to the extent required by the Public Records Act 2005. MBIE may also be required to disclose information under the Official Information Act 1982 or to a Parliamentary Select Committee or Parliament in response to a Parliamentary Question.

## Security

MBIE websites have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. In order to maintain the cyber security of MBIE systems and information, MBIE systems are subject to ongoing monitoring (including activity logging), analysis and auditing. We may use information about your use of our websites and other IT systems to prevent unauthorised access or attacks on these systems or to resolve such events. We may use this information even if you are not involved in such activity. MBIE may utilise services from one or more 3rd party suppliers to monitor or maintain the cyber security of its systems and information. These 3rd party suppliers will have access to monitoring and logging information as well as information processed on MBIE websites and other IT systems.

## Call recording

As part of our commitment to providing the best possible service to our customers we record all telephone calls answered in our contact centre. This helps us to identify ways that we can provide you with a better service.

We record calls:

  * for staff training purposes, helping us to improve the quality of our customer service and to ensure the information we provide is consistent and accurate;
  * so we can find ways to simplify our service to you; and
  * to ensure we have an accurate record of your call, which may be needed to support any transactions that take place over the phone and/or if there is a dispute.

We understand your personal information is important to you, and we are committed to protecting your privacy. We store the recordings securely for two years and destroy them after this period.

Unless we have lawful reason for withholding this information, it will be made available if you request access to a transcript of your call by phoning 0508 266 726 and asking for the Privacy Officer.

### Business.govt.nz calendar

Please note that the Business.govt.nz calendar is a service provided by Trumba Corporation (Trumba). If you choose to use the Event Actions function in the calendar, for example to subscribe to a calendar, request calendar reminders, or download calendar information, you may be prompted by Trumba to provide personal information such as your name and email address. Personal information provided to Trumba is subject to the Trumba Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

When you use Trumba Events Actions you consent to the Trumba Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions of Use.

###   
Companies Office Search Results

Business.govt.nz provides visitors the opportunity to search the New Zealand Companies Register through a web service, with results displayed on the Business.govt.nz website. Public information held on the Companies Register includes director and shareholder names and addresses which may appear on Business.govt.nz as the result of a search.  

### Compliance Matters

The Compliance Matters tool requires users to provide an email address to save an action list and send reminders.  Business.govt.nz does not collect or store these email addresses.  Some browsers may auto fill an email address previously entered if the cache has not been cleared but this is not related to any action by Business.govt.nz.

MBIE will be collecting statistics from the Compliance Matters tool including information on items saved to action lists.    
This information is not associated with individuals and cannot be traced back to an email address used to save an action list.

###   
Employee Cost Calculator

The Employee Cost Calculator tool requires users to provide an email address to email their calculation results.  Business.govt.nz does not collect or store these email addresses.  Some browsers may auto fill an email address previously entered if the cache has not been cleared but this is not related to any action by Business.govt.nz.

MBIE will be collecting statistics from the Employee Cost Calculator tool including information on refinements made by users to the calculation results.  This information is not associated with individuals and cannot be traced back to an email address used to save an action list.

###   
Employment Agreement Builder

The Employment Agreement Builder (EAB) tool requires users to send their completed agreements to a secure email address. Users will also be asked for an email address if they start an employment agreement and intend to finish it at a later date. These email addresses will be used to send users a link to return to their draft agreement. Business.govt.nz will temporarily store this email address until the agreement has been completed. Once the user completes their employment agreement, their email address will be permanently deleted from Business.govt.nz.

In the event that a user does not complete an employment agreement, private information, eg employer and employee names, will be automatically deleted. Users will have to retype these fields when they return to their draft agreement. Any draft agreement that hasn’t been reopened in 90 days will be automatically deleted.

Once a user has completed their employment agreement, all information will be permanently deleted from Business.govt.nz.

MBIE will be collecting statistics from the EAB tool. This information is not associated with individuals and cannot be traced back to an email address used to create an agreement.  

## Rights of access and correction

### Your rights

You have the right to:

  * find out from us whether we hold personal information about you
  * access that information; and, if applicable
  * request corrections to that information.

If MBIE has a good reason for refusing a request for correction, you are entitled to request that a statement be attached to the information of the correction that was sought but not made.

If you want to check personal information that we hold, please write to:

Privacy Officer  
Companies Office  
Northern Business Centre  
Private Bag 92061  
Victoria Street West  
Auckland 1142.

For more information on the privacy laws in New Zealand and contact details for the Office of the Privacy Commissioner, please visit the [Privacy Commissioner's website](https://opcwebsite.cwp.govt.nz/ "\[link to Privacy Commissioner's website\]. ").

## Statistical information and cookies

### Statistical information

We may collect statistical information about your visit to help us improve this site. This information is aggregated and non-personally identifying. It includes:

  * your IP address;
  * the search terms you used;
  * the pages you accessed on our Site and the links you clicked on;
  * the date and time you visited the site;
  * the referring site (if any) through which you clicked through to this Site;
  * the device you used to access the site;
  * your operating system (e.g. Windows XP, Mac OSX);
  * the type of web browser you use (e.g. Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox); and
  * their incidental matters such as screen resolution, the release of your installed Flash version and the language setting of your browser.

The statistical information referred to above will be viewable by site administrators and certain other MBIE staff. It may also be shared with other government agencies.

### Cookies

Browser or ‘web’ cookies are small text files that are sent by a website and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are generally used to improve your experience of a website (e.g. by remembering preferences you have set) and to track site usage.

MBIE does not use cookies on this website to gather any personally identifiable information. We use cookies to gather data about trends in site usage using a tool called Google Analytics. We also use cookies to gather data about your browsing history on the MBIE website. We may use this data to enhance your browsing experience, improve our website, identify whether you have seen our marketing material before you visited our site, and target advertising to you.

The types of Advertising Features implemented on the MBIE website may include:

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics
  * Google Display Impression Reporting
  * DoubleClick Platform integrations
  * Google Analytics Demographics and Interest reporting.  

You can read Google’s privacy statement, and access a Google Analytics opt-out tool, at the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ "\[link to Google website\] Privacy and terms. ").

You can manually disable cookies at any time - check your browser's 'Help' to find out how (disabling cookies will not affect your ability to use this website).

[Contact us](http://www.business.govt.nz/about-this-site/contact-business.govt.nz "\[internal link\] Contact us. ") if you have an enquiry or concern about our privacy policy.
